const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",a="accounting",o=200,i=120,t=[{id:386,question:"Which of the following items is not treated in the Profit and Loss Account?",option:{a:"Office expenses",b:"Salaries and allowances",c:"Carriage inwards",d:"Discounts allowed"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:256,question:"Rent expenses for the year 2005 is",option:{a:"N 11,400",b:"N  11,300",c:"N  11,200",d:"N  10,200."},section:"Rent accrued 1st January, 2005 [600], Rent paid in 2005 [11,300], Rent prepaid 31st December, 2005 [500]",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:269,question:"Which of the following is an example of factory overheads?",option:{a:"Salary of marketing officer",b:"Salary of production officer",c:"Salary of accounting officer",d:"Wages of machine operator"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:254,question:"Where the head office maintains all books of account, goods sent to branch is credited to",option:{a:"Goods Sent to Branch Account",b:"Branch Stock Account",c:"Branch Stock Adjustment Account",d:"Head Office Current Account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:477,question:"The accounting convention which states that the performance of a business should be determined by matching all expenses against all revenues is",option:{a:"accruals",b:"materiality",c:"objectivity",d:"periodicity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:383,question:"Calculate the stock figure to be included in the balance sheet at the year end.",option:{a:"D408,000",b:"D346,000",c:"D284,000",d:"D62,000"},section:" Use the following information to answer question: Branch stock account (at selling price)  D346,000 - debit Branch mark-up account D62,000 - debit",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:3,question:"Where a proprietor withdraws cash from the business for his private use, the entries would be ",option:{a:"credit cash account, debit proprietor's account ",b:"credit proprietor's account, debit cash account ",c:"credit proprietor's account, debit   drawings   account    ",d:"credit   cash account,  debit drawings account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:105,question:"A low current ratio in a business indicates that the business is",option:{a:"faced with long term loan repayment problem.",b:"efficient in the utilization of its resources.",c:"unable to pay its bills on time.",d:"growing its net asset effectively."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:247,question:"Using the reducing balance method, the depreciation charged for year 2003 was",option:{a:"N  160,000",b:"N  150,000",c:"N   130,000",d:"N  120,000"},section:"Motor vehicles (at cost) 1/1/2002   [N1,000,000],  Addition to motor vehicles 1/7/2003  [N  600,000] 	Depreciation rate 10%",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:278,question:"Which of the following is not an input device?",option:{a:"Card reader",b:"Paper top reader",c:"Alpha-numeric keyboard",d:"Line printer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:240,question:"Cost of goods manufactured is",option:{a:"D138,000",b:"D131,800",c:"D130,500",d:"D123,000."},section:"Given Opening stock:  raw materials [10,000 ], work-in-progress [16,000],  Purchases of raw materials [95,500] , Direct labour wages paid [13,500], Royalties paid [6,200], Accrued wages[2,800], Closing stock- raw materials [7,500], work-in-progress[ 8,500], 	Manufacturing overhead [10,000]",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:500,question:"Receipts and payments account is a summary of the",option:{a:"budget",b:"trading account",c:"cash book",d:"profit and loss account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:306,question:"Purchase invoice is first entered in the",option:{a:"purchases account",b:"cash book",c:"sales journal",d:"purchase journal"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:187,question:"Where a business is purchased, the full amount of the purchase consideration is credited to",option:{a:"Purchase of Business Account",b:"Creditor’s Account",c:"Vendor’s Account",d:"Purchaser’s Account."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:19,question:"A statement that shows the financial position of a business is ",option:{a:"profit and loss account  ",b:"Trading Account ",c:"Statement of income  ",d:" Balance sheet"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:316,question:"Which of the following expresses the accounting equating?",option:{a:"Capital + Assets = Liabilities",b:"Assets - Liabilities = Capital",c:"Liabilities + Current Assets = Fixed Assets",d:"Liabilities - Capital = Current Assets"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:348,question:"An example of a credit entry in a profit and loss account is",option:{a:"carriage inwards",b:"carriage outwards",c:"discounts allowed",d:"discounts received"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:149,question:"A discount that is allowed to encourage a debtor to pay off his debt within a period is the",option:{a:"trade discount",b:"annual discount",c:"periodic discount",d:"cash discount."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:372,question:"Which of the following items is not contained in the Receipts and Payments Account?",option:{a:"Subscription paid in advance",b:"tock paid for in advance",c:"Outstanding wages and salaries",d:"Donations"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:135,question:"The documents that provide instant information to firms on their transactions with banks are",option:{a:"bank statement and debit note",b:"cheque stub and deposit slip",c:"cheque book and cashbook",d:"payslip and credit invoice."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:47,question:"The balance unearned rent account for Jones Co. as at 31st Dec. is 1,200. If Jones Co tailed to record the adjusting entry for 600 of rent earned during December, the effect on the balance sheet and income statement",option:{a:"for December is:",b:" Liabilities   overstated—N60Q:   c:et income overstate d 44600",c:" Liabilities   understated   £4500:   net income  understated N600",d:"Asset    understated—N600:     net    income  overstated N600"},section:" Liabilities   overstated   N600:    net income understated N600",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:200,question:"An expense becomes an accrual because it",option:{a:"is due for payment",b:"is a Profit and Loss Account item",c:"is a Trading Account item",d:"is to be paid within the next one year"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:488,question:"Determine the capital of the business",option:{a:"N 9,400",b:"N 6,000",c:"N 3,400",d:"N 3,000"},section:"Use the information to answer question: Total current assets [N2,000 ]; Total fixed assets [N 4,000 ]; Current liabilities [N 1,200 ]; Drawings [N 200 ]; Long-term loan 	[N 2,000 ]",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:425,question:"What is Kunle’s share of the profit?",option:{a:"N 600",b:"N 300",c:"N180",d:"N 120"},section:"Jumoke and Kunle have an original investment of N 25,000 and N15,000 respectively in a partnership.   The articles of partnership provide 3% interest on capital and salaries of N1,500 and N 1,000 respectively for the partners.   The profits and losses are to be shared in the ratio 3:2. Miscellaneous expenses of N 2,500 were incurred with gross profit of N 6,500 during the financial year.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:174,question:"To correct an error, the Purchases Account was debited while Suspense Account was credited. Which  of  the following was the cause of the error?",option:{a:"Under casting of purchases",b:"Overcasting of purchases",c:"Original entry.",d:"Transportation of returns outwards"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:39,question:"Subscription   received   in   respect of a future period is",option:{a:"Subscription deposit",b:"Subscription in advance",c:"Accrued subscription",d:"Subscription in arrears"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:59,question:"If a business pays for only 11 months rent during a financial year, what accounting term is given to the outstanding term is given to the outstanding one month's rent? Which of the following equations properly represents a derivation of the fundamental accounting equation?",option:{a:"Assets + liabilities = owner's equity ",b:"Assets = owner's equity",c:"Cash = assets.  ",d:"Assets - liabilities = owner's equity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:369,question:"A petty cash account has an imprest of D28,000. The account has a debit balance of D5.000. How much cash is needed to restore the imprest?",option:{a:"D33,000",b:"D28,000",c:"D23,000",d:"D5,000"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:358,question:"Which of the following is entered in the general journal?",option:{a:"Purchase of goods",b:"Sale of goods on credit",c:"Returns inwards",d:"Acquisition of fixed assets"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:162,question:"When the purchase Consideration is lower than the net asset, the buyer has gained the advantage of",option:{a:"capital reserve",b:"revenue reserve",c:"net-income",d:"net loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:191,question:"The double entry required for the mark-up is debit Branch",option:{a:"Sales Account, credit Branch Adjustment Account",b:"Adjustment Account, credit Branch Stock Account",c:"Stock Account, credit Branch Adjustment Account",d:"Profit and Loss Account, credit Branch Stock Account,"},section:"A company charges out goods to a branch at cost plus 25 percent.  It invoiced  N 12,000 worth of goods",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:435,question:"Calculate the total figure for the receipts and payments account.",option:{a:"N 11,410",b:"N  13,630",c:"N  9, 310",d:"N  11, 530."},section:"Entrance fees [N 1,200 ]; Subscription (including N 850 arrears) [N 4,310 ]; Donations received [N 1,500]; Proceeds from sales [N 2 ,300]; Total payments [N 8,200 ]; Depreciation [N 2,100]; Closing cash balance [N 1,110 ]. The club deposited 200% of the closing cash balance in the bank during the period.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:218,question:"A sales ledger contains",option:{a:"creditors’ accounts",b:"nominal accounts",c:"real accounts",d:"debtors’ accounts."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:359,question:"The cost of carriage outward is classified as",option:{a:"a selling and distribution expense",b:"an administrative expense",c:"a trading expense",d:"a finance expense"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:297,question:"Administrative, selling and distribution expenses in a 	manufacturing firm are recorded in",option:{a:"Trading Account.",b:"Manufacturing Account.",c:"Profit and Loss Account.",d:"Balance Sheet."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:285,question:"The Sales Ledger Control Account is also referred to as",option:{a:"Bought Ledger Control Account.",b:"Purchases Account.",c:"Total Debtors Account.",d:"Total Creditors Account."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:380,question:"The accounting concept which states that expenditure involving insignificant amounts should be regarded as expenses and not assets is",option:{a:"business entity",b:"materiality",c:"dual aspect",d:"realization"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:186,question:"Which of the following is an advantage of the imprest system?",option:{a:"Making high profits in the business",b:"Rewarding the imprest holder",c:"Easy preparation of the final accounts",d:"Meeting small items of expenditure"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:142,question:"A proprietor started business with N13, 000.  Assets and liabilities at the end of the year; fixed assets N8, 800, stock N2, 600, debtors  N1 , 000, cash N3, 000 and creditors N1 , 000. Determine the profit for the year?",option:{a:"N2, 400",b:"N3, 000",c:"N9, 800",d:"N 1 , 400"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:511,question:"Expenditure incurred on consumables and goods for resale is",option:{a:"revenue expenditure",b:"capital expenditure",c:"sunk cost",d:"miscellaneous expenses"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:266,question:"which of the following is a Trading Account item?",option:{a:"Discounts allowed",b:"Discounts received",c:"Carriage outwards",d:"Carriage inwards"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:507,question:"The share premium account would be",option:{a:"credited with application and allotment  N 187,500",b:"debited with application and allotment  N 375,000",c:"credited with application and allotment  N 375,000",d:"debited with application and allotment  N 187,500"},section:"Use the information below to answer questions 43 and 44	 A company advertised and issued 750,000,12% preference shares of  N 1 each to be issued at  N 1.50 per share. Applications for 1,370,000 were received at 30k per share. 70k per share (including premium) was due on allotment while 25k per share was due on each of the remaining two calls. All amounts due were received. Application money for 120,000 shares was refunded to unsuccessful applicants and the remaining applicants were allotted shares on pro-rata basis.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:37,question:"Which of the following is not a business asset?",option:{a:"Deposit account in bank",b:"Interest due on loan",c:"Five acres of land",d:"Library books owned by a lawyer "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:82,question:"credit balance is",option:{a:"a liability or an expense.",b:"a liability or an income.",c:"an expenditure or an income.",d:"an asset or an expense."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:34,question:"Where a correct amount is entered, but in the wrong person's account, is an error of  ",option:{a:"Principle  ",b:" Omission",c:"Commission",d:"Compensation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:70,question:"Posting  the  transactions   in bookkeeping means ",option:{a:"making the first entry of a double entry transaction ",b:"entering items in a cash book ",c:"making the second  entry of a double entry transaction ",d:"something other than the above."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:65,question:"MORADE had total assets of N760,000, capital stock of N150,000 and retained earnings of N215,000. What was Morade's debt-to-equity ratio? ",option:{a:"2.63",b:"1.08",c:"0.52",d:"0.48"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:180,question:"In a partnership goodwill is recognized when",option:{a:"a new partner is admitted",b:"a partner is dormant",c:"the business is making huge profit",d:"the business has good customer relations"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:264,question:"A Balance Sheet shows only",option:{a:"fixed assets and current assets",b:"assets and long term liabilities.",c:"assets and liabilities",d:"assets and capital"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:497,question:"The costs incurred by departments that support the production department with such activities as maintenance, production control and storage are called",option:{a:"autonomous costs",b:"service costs",c:"supporting costs",d:"subsidiary costs"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:444,question:"An accounting ratio that considers only quick assets to determine the short-term safety margin of a firm is the",option:{a:"fixed assets ratio",b:"capital gearing ratio",c:"current assets ratio",d:"acid test ratio."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:384,question:"The concept applied in answering question 42 above is",option:{a:"matching",b:"consistency",c:"prudence",d:"entity"},section:" Use the following information to answer question: Branch stock account (at selling price)  D346,000 - debit Branch mark-up account D62,000 - debit",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:185,question:"In Manufacturing Account, prime cost plus factory overhead is known as",option:{a:"conversion cost",b:"cost of raw materials consumed",c:"total cost",d:"production cost"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:118,question:"The prime cost is",option:{a:"GHc 64,500.",b:"GHc 64,000.",c:"GHc 58,500.",d:"GHc 52,500."},section:"Use the following information to answer question:  Stock of raw materials 1/1/09  [ 5,000 ], Stock of raw materials 31/12/09   [ 5,500], Purchase of raw materials [ 50,000], Carriage inwards [3,000], Direct labour [ 12,000], Factory overhead [17,500]",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:91,question:"The returns on capital employed is",option:{a:"17.2%",b:"16.2%.",c:"15.2%.",d:"11.2%."},section:"Use the following information to answer question. Net profit [ 60,000], Total Assets [ 520,000], Current liabilities [ 150,000], Current assets[ 280,000] ",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:75,question:" Impersonal accounts contain ",option:{a:"capital and cash account ",b:"nominal account and real account ",c:" real and cash account ",d:"capital and real act minis "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:399,question:"The three-column cash book differs from the two-column cash book in",option:{a:"cash column",b:"discount column",c:"bank column",d:"folio column"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:284,question:"Which of the following is not found in the personal ledger?",option:{a:"Debtors Account",b:"Creditors Account",c:"Capital Account",d:"Nominal Account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:498,question:"Determine the gross profit",option:{a:"N 49,000",b:"N 48,000",c:"N 31,000",d:"N30,000"},section:"Use the information to answer questions: Work-in-progress 1/1[N 1,000 ];	Work-in-progress 31/12 	[N 2,000 ]; Production cost of goods manufactured 	[N 20,000 ] Sales [N 50,000]; Stock of finished goods 1/1 [N 4,000 ]; Stock of finished goods 31/12 [N 5,000 ]; Selling and distribution expenses[  N 2,000 ]; Administrative expenses [ 1,000 ]",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:115,question:"In a not-for-profit making organization, the cash book is referred to as",option:{a:"income and expenditure account.",b:"receipts and payments account.",c:"two column cash book.",d:"petty cash book."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:490,question:"Which of the following items are current assets?",option:{a:"Stock, bills receivable, cash and debtors",b:"Stock, bills payable, cash and debtors",c:"Stock, bad debt, bills receivable and cash",d:"Stock, work-in-progress, cash and bills payable."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:415,question:"The accumulated fund is",option:{a:"N 9,400",b:"N 9,300",c:"N 9,200",d:"N 9,100"},section:"On January 1, 2000, a club’s assets and liabilities were as follows: Club house [ N8,000 ]; Subscription in arrears [ N300]; Cash [N1,000]; Wages owed [N100]. The club has 50 members and annual subscription is N 100 per member. Subscription received is N 4,000 and this includes 1999 arrears of  N 200.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:208,question:"The purchase consideration was",option:{a:"N  24,000",b:"N 23,000",c:"N  20,000",d:"N 15,000"},section:"A business whose assets consisted of stock  N 15,000 and debtors   N  8,000 was bought by issuing 20,000 ordinary shares of   N  1 each at a premium of  20 percent.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:438,question:"I.Profits and losses will be shared unequally II.  Interest is not allowed on capital, III. Salaries are not allowed. IV. Interest is charged on drawings. Which of  the following would apply where there is no agreement during partnership formation?",option:{a:"I only",b:"I, II and III",c:"I, II and IV",d:"II and III."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:73,question:"Companies and  Allied  Matters  Act. 1990 requires  every  company   to  keep  certain statutory books. Which of the following is not part of the statutory books to be kept by the company? ",option:{a:"register of directors and secretaries ",b:"a register of charges (fixed and floating) ",c:"minutes books of meetings of the company and meetings of its directors ",d:"a register of companies in the same line of business"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:459,question:"What was the asset value at the beginning of the third year?",option:{a:"N 63 m",b:"N 133 m",c:"N 36m",d:"N 28 m."},section:"An asset was purchased for  N 343 m in 2003. The estimated life of the asset was 3 years with a residual value of  N28 m.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:227,question:"Cross referencing among different books of accounts is achieved with the use of",option:{a:"columns",b:"reference numbers",c:"folio",d:"margin."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:337,question:"Which of the following expenses is allocated according to the floor 	area?",option:{a:"Wages and Salaries",b:"Rent and rates",c:"Canteen expenses",d:"Discount allowed"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:202,question:"The person, who is responsible for the formation of a company is called the",option:{a:"promoter",b:"sponsor",c:"shareholder",d:"director"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:388,question:"A manufacturing account is drawn up by",option:{a:"firms providing personal services",b:"firms engaged solely in buying and selling of goods",c:"firms which make and sell articles",d:"non - trading organization."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:327,question:"The accounting concept that allows the cost of kitchen cutlery to be expensed, though it will be used for more than one year is",option:{a:"materiality",b:"accrual",c:"going concern",d:"business entity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:241,question:"A set of instructions fed into a computer for accomplishing a given task is a/an",option:{a:"input",b:"programme",c:"output",d:"data."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:11,question:"The journal is a book ",option:{a:"of primary entry into which all transactions are entered before posting ",b:"kept by journalist for reporting events ",c:"of prime entry into which postings are made from the ledger  ",d:"of analyzing major accounts"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:508,question:"The second and final call account was debited with",option:{a:"ordinary share capital account  N 187,500",b:"12% preference share capital  N  375,000",c:"bank account  N 187,500",d:"12% preference share capital account  N 187,500"},section:"Use the information below to answer questions 43 and 44	 A company advertised and issued 750,000,12% preference shares of  N 1 each to be issued at  N 1.50 per share. Applications for 1,370,000 were received at 30k per share. 70k per share (including premium) was due on allotment while 25k per share was due on each of the remaining two calls. All amounts due were received. Application money for 120,000 shares was refunded to unsuccessful applicants and the remaining applicants were allotted shares on pro-rata basis.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:463,question:"The provision for bad debt is",option:{a:"N2 000",b:"N 800",c:"N3 000",d:"N1 900."},section:"Use the information below to answer question: Debtors [N20 000]; Provision for bad debts 10%; Provision for discount on debtors 5%.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:148,question:"When the fixed capital method is used, the partners share of profits and remunerations are credited to the",option:{a:"current account.",b:"profit and Loss account.",c:"profit and loss appropriation account.",d:"capital account."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:428,question:"The expenses incurred in promoting a company are",option:{a:"promoters’ expenses",b:"floating expenses",c:"preliminary expenses",d:"the Board’s expenses"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:26,question:"Which of the following is not a book of original entry? ",option:{a:"Cash book  ",b:"Purchases journal  ",c:"Sales journal ",d:"Ledger"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:98,question:"Which of the following is recorded on the debit side of the Trial Balance?",option:{a:"Bank overdraft",b:"Returns outwards",c:"Purchases",d:"Capital"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:363,question:"Net profit in a business is",option:{a:"the amount of money taken out of the business by the owner",b:"the cash in the business bank account",c:"the difference between sales and cost of sales",d:"sale revenue less cost of sales and expenses"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:504,question:"Which of the following is a common cause of a discrepancy between head office and branch trial balance?",option:{a:"Debtors and cash in transit",b:"Creditors and cash in transit",c:"Stock and cash in transit",d:"Stock and prepayments"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:271,question:"Branch Stock Account is used to determine the",option:{a:"net value of goods sent to branch.",b:"gross profit of the branch.",c:"branch credit sales.",d:"branch net profit or loss."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:18,question:"Trading account is prepared to ascertain ",option:{a:"Gross profit ",b:"Net profit ",c:"Gross profit or Gross loss ",d:" Net profit or net loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:184,question:"The prof it on sale was",option:{a:"N=  8,000",b:"N=  7,000",c:"N=  6,000",d:"N=  1,000."},section:"An asset was bought on 1st January, 1992 for N= 20,000. Depreciation was provided for annually at 20% on cost. It was sold for N= 7,000 on 1st July, 1995.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:360,question:"The purchase of ten ceiling fans by Akpan Electronic Enterprises will be recorded as",option:{a:"an acquisition of fixed asset",b:"an expense in its general office expense account",c:"part of capital in the capital account",d:"an acquisition of stock"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:57,question:"The purchase journal records:",option:{a:"invoices from creditors",b:"Debtors' invoices",c:"Cash payments to suppliers",d:"Amounts owing to employees for wage;"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:329,question:"The accounting concept that states that a firm’s financial affairs must be separated from that of the owner’s private transactions is",option:{a:"business entity",b:"going concern",c:"consistency",d:"duality"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:318,question:"Unpresented cheques are cheque",option:{a:"that have been recorded in the cash book, but not by the bank",b:"that have been received by the bank, but recorded in the cash book",c:"returned by the bank",d:"written, but not handed over to customers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:44,question:"A company provided the following information about its balance sheet: Cash N100 Accounts receivable N500 Stockholders' equity 14700 Account payable N200 Bank loans Nl000 Based on the information provided, how much are Remington's liabilities?",option:{a:"N200   ",b:"N900   ",c:"N 1,200   ",d:"N 1,700"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:423,question:"On dissolution, the final distribution of cash to partners is based on",option:{a:"partnership agreement",b:"Articles of Association",c:"goodwill",d:"capital balances."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:93,question:"Which of the following is a nominal account?",option:{a:"Machinery Account",b:"Drawings Account",c:"Debtors Account",d:"Wages Account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:192,question:"A ledger is a",option:{a:"book of accounts",b:"summary of entries",c:"book of original entry",d:"double entry posting"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:480,question:"What is the total debit for the trial balance?",option:{a:"N  4 690 000",b:"N 2 620 000",c:"N  2 520 000",d:"N 1 565 000"},section:"Given: Capital [N 2, 375, 000 ]; Debtors [N 495, 000 ]; Motor vehicles [N 870, 000 ]; Creditors [N 245,000 ]; Prepayments [N 500, 000 ]; Bills receivable [N 505, 000 ]; Furniture [N 150, 000 ]",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:392,question:"The accounting principle that is applied to check arbitrary actions on the part of accountants is",option:{a:"consistency",b:"materiality",c:"objectivity",d:"realization"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:452,question:"Find the salary charged to Zera product.",option:{a:"N 1 854",b:"N 1 845",c:"N 1 062",d:"N 1 134."},section:"Lighting [N2, 925]; Rent [ N2, 640]; Salary [N4, 050] The expenses are for three different products: Zema, Zeta and Zera. They are apportioned on the basis of production. 4500 units of the products are produced, out of which 1260 and 2060 units are for Zema and Zeta respectively.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:350,question:"The accounting treatment for a dishonoured cheque is; debit",option:{a:"Customer’s Account; Credit Bank Account",b:"Bank Account; Credit Customer’s Account",c:"Customer’s Account; Credit Sales Account",d:"Sales Account; Credit Customer’s Account\\"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:132,question:"The ratio that gives the indication of the efficiency of a firm’s sales with respect to cost of goods sold is a",option:{a:"return on capital employed",b:"gross profit margin",c:"net profit margin",d:"return on equity."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:422,question:"Transfers from the head office to branches are best carried out at",option:{a:"cost price",b:"selling price",c:"cost plus mark-up",d:"market price"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:412,question:"Cost classification in relation to charges is determined by the level of",option:{a:"raw materials",b:"labour",c:"activity",d:"profitability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:397,question:"The recipient whose name appears on a cheque is called a",option:{a:"payee",b:"drawer",c:"drawee",d:"payee"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:441,question:"Expenses paid during the conversion of a partnership to a 	company are",option:{a:"debited to the partners’ capital account",b:"debited to the realization account",c:"debited to the cash account.",d:"credited to the realization account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:231,question:"Bank reconciliation statement reconciles",option:{a:"bank and cash balances in the cash book",b:"bank balance in the cash book and bank statement balance",c:"cash balance in the cash book and bank statement balance",d:"bank balance brought down and bank balance carried down in the cash bcok."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:440,question:"Determine the closing stock.",option:{a:"N 5 500",b:"N  6500",c:"N 2500",d:"N 4500"},section:"Use the information below to answer questions: Stock (1/1/02) at selling price [N2, 000 ]; Goods sent to branch (selling price)    [  ?  ]; Sales by branch (selling price)   [4, 500 ]; Stock (31/12/02)   [  	?    ] Opening stock is 1/4 of goods sent to branch.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:155,question:"The trader’s capital in a single entry system is ascertained by preparing",option:{a:"gross profit",b:"statement of affairs",c:"suspense account",d:"appropriation account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:321,question:"In preparing a profit and loss account, a decrease in provision for doubtful debts accounts is treated as",option:{a:"Currentability",b:"expenses",c:"Income",d:"Current asset"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:33,question:"Which of the following does not appear in a bank statement?   ",option:{a:"Uncredited cheque ",b:"Bank charges ",c:"Dishonoured cheque ",d:" Dividend   received   on    behalf   of customer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:121,question:"Upon the dissolution of a partnership business, the party to be settled first out of the proceeds realized is",option:{a:"unsecured creditors.",b:"partners’ loan and advances.",c:"secured creditors.",d:"partners’ capital."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:343,question:"Which of the following is a spreadsheet application?",option:{a:"Excel",b:"Word",c:"Internet",d:"Windows"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:206,question:"Rent receivable is a",option:{a:"current asset",b:"current liability",c:"contingent liability",d:"fictitious asset"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:100,question:"Cash receipts and payments involving discounts are entered in",option:{a:"three-column cash book.",b:"two-column cash book.",c:"analytical cash book.",d:"petty cash book."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:434,question:"A company has departments X, Y and Z. Department X occupies a space twice that of Y while Z   occupies half the space of  Y. If the company pays N 70 000 on rent, what is the amount of rent that should be allocated to Y?",option:{a:"N 30,000",b:"N 40,000",c:"N 20,000",d:"N 10, 000."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:255,question:"Which of the following is not a purpose for preparing departmental accounts? To",option:{a:"compare the results of different departments",b:"employ staff into different departments",c:"reward departmental managers",d:"obtain information for formulating policies."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:8,question:"At the end of a trading period, wages will be  ",option:{a:"debited to trading account and shown as a current liability ",b:"credited to profit and loss Account and shown as a current liability ",c:"credited to trading account and shown as a current asset ",d:"debited to profit and loss account and shown as a current liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:299,question:"The capital is",option:{a:"D7,580",b:"D6,580",c:"D5,380",d:"D1,000"},section:"Use the following information to answer questions:: Cash in hand	[D 1,440]; Cash at Bank [D 2,440]; Stock [D 2,500]; Furniture and fittings [D 2,200]; Creditors [D 1,000]",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:413,question:"The gross profit on manufacture is",option:{a:"N 6,120",b:"N 6,100",c:"N 5,100",d:"N 5,000"},section:"Materials consumed 	[N 16,600 ]; Direct cost  [N 5,400 ]; Factory rent  [N 2,300 ]; Factory lighting 	[N 1,200]. Cost of production to be transferred at cost plus 20% mark-up.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:119,question:"Which of the following relates to the essence of partnership? To",option:{a:"run a charity organization.",b:"pursue a social objective.",c:"form a business for profit.",d:"run a religious objective."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:63,question:" An expenditure whose benefit is finished or enjoyed immediately is called: ",option:{a:"Expense   ",b:"Liability ",c:"Cost ",d:"Income"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:205,question:"Where there are no proper books of account, the capital at the commencement of a period is ascertained by preparing",option:{a:"Total Debtors and Creditors Accounts",b:"Bank Reconciliation Statement",c:"Statement of Affairs",d:"Trading, Profit and Loss Accounts"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:481,question:"If Odukoya takes money out of the business bank account for his own private use, the effect of the transaction is",option:{a:"increase in assets and increase in capital",b:"increase in assets and decrease in capital",c:"decrease in capital and increase in assets",d:"decrease in capital and decrease in assets."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:234,question:"Revenue is recognized in the profit and loss account as soon as a",option:{a:"debtor pays what is due from him",b:"sale of goods takes place and money is received",c:"sale of goods takes place whether or not money is received",d:"sale of a fixed asset takes place."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"}],s={message:e,subject:a,status:200,total:120,data:t};export{t as data,s as default,e as message,o as status,a as subject,i as total};
